Billy Pilgrim lives —from time to time to time…
Slaughterhouse-Five is a drama, science fiction, war
film directed by George Roy Hill.
Billy Pilgrim, a veteran of the Second World War, finds himself mysteriously detached from time, so that he is able to travel, without being able to help it, from the days of his childhood to those of his peculiar
life on a distant planet called Tralfamadore, passing through his bitter experience as a prisoner of war in the German city of Dresden, over which looms the inevitable shadow of an unspeakable tragedy.
Billy Pilgrim, played by Michael Sacks.
Paul Lazzaro, played by Ron Leibman.
Derby, played by Eugene Roche.
Valencia, played by Sharon Gans.
Montana Wildhack, played by Valerie Perrine.
Barbara, played by Holly Near.
Slaughterhouse-Five is a 1972 American comedy-drama military science fiction film directed by George Roy Hill and produced by
Paul Monash, from a screenplay by Stephen Geller, based on the 1969 novel of the same name by Kurt Vonnegut.
The film stars Michael Sacks as Billy Pilgrim, who is "unstuck in
time" and has no control over where he is going next.
It also stars Ron Leibman as Paul Lazzaro and
Valerie Perrine as Montana Wildhack.
Slaughterhouse-Five premiered at the 25th Cannes Film Festival, where it
won the Jury Prize and was nominated for the Palme d'Or.
The film also won a Hugo Award for Best Dramatic Presentation and the
inaugural Saturn Award for Best Science Fiction Film.
Sacks was nominated for a Golden Globe Award for Most Promising
Newcomer – Male for his portrayal of Pilgrim.
Vonnegut wrote about the film soon after its release, in his preface to Between Time and Timbuktu: "I love George Roy Hill
and Universal Pictures, who made a flawless translation of my novel Slaughterhouse-Five to the silver screen.
I drool and cackle every time I watch that film, because it is so
harmonious with what I felt when I wrote the book."
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, based on novel
or book, war crimes, world war ii, prisoner of war.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.